These stretchy metals can cool their surroundings. Could this be the future of refrigeration? So
everything that has to do with refrigeration and air conditioning is done by vapor compression
technology, where this chemical refrigerant called hydrofluorocarbon, it absorbs and releases
latent heat. Except the problem is that hydrofluorocarbon, it's contributing
significantly to the global warming problem. And that's why we started
thinking that we can make cooling devices by stretching nickel titanium wire. So we stretch
it and it actually release heat and you unstretch it's cooling its surrounding.
But it hadn't been a prevalent phenomenon that was well known. So when we first
approached the Department of Energy they said, as far as we know, no such phenomenon
exists. And so that's when we said exactly, you should let us try it.